connectforhealthco.com 2016-10-15

# Privacy Policy - Connect for Health Colorado

## Connect for Health Colorado Privacy Policy

Protecting your privacy is very important to us. We’re telling you about Connect for Health Colorado’s privacy policy so you know what information we collect, why we collect it, and what we do with it.

Connectforhealthco.com doesn’t collect any personally identifiable information (PII) about you during your visit to our website unless you choose to provide it to us. We do, however, collect information from visitors who read, browse, and/or download information from our site. We do this so we can understand how the public uses the site and how to make it more helpful. We will not knowingly disclose your personal information to a third party, except as provided in this statement.

## Types of information we collect

Connect for Health Colorado (the Marketplace) will keep the information you provide private as required by law. The information you provide will be used for the purposes of enrollment in a plan; treatment; payment; determining eligibility; or other purposes permitted by law.

As part of the process, we will communicate with you or your authorized representative, and then provide the information to the health plan you select so that they can enroll those who are eligible in a qualified health plan. Information on race and ethnicity will not be provided to the insurance carriers, unless you are an American Indian or Alaska Native because that information could positively affect your benefits. We will verify your answers using information in our electronic databases and the databases of partner agencies. If the information you provide does not match these sources, we may ask you to send us proof of the information you provide.

Health insurance carriers can no longer deny coverage based on your health status.  Households that are not seeking financial assistance and have members who are not seeking insurance will not be asked questions about citizenship or immigration status.

If you don’t have an exemption from the shared responsibility payment and you don’t maintain qualifying health insurance for three months or longer during the year, you may be subject to a federal penalty.

**Important** : Connect for Health Colorado is authorized to collect information on the application, including Social Security numbers, and will confirm information that may affect initial or ongoing eligibility for all persons listed on your application. You are allowing Connect for Health Colorado to use Social Security numbers and other information from your application to request and receive information or records to confirm the information in your application.   You release Connect for Health Colorado from all liability for sharing this information with other agencies for this purpose. For example, Connect for Health Colorado may get and share your information with any of the following agencies: Social Security Administration; United States Customs and Immigration Services; Department of Homeland Security; Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; other federal or state agencies; and Agents/Brokers and managing general agencies contracting with those agents/brokers, as applicable, which are certified by the Marketplace to assist applicants/enrollees. We need this information to check your eligibility for health insurance and to give you the best service possible if you choose to apply. Regulations that support getting this data can be found  under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (Public Law 111-148), as amended by the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (Public Law 111-152), the Social Security Act, and Colorado S.B. 11-200, the Colorado Health Benefit Exchange Act, codified at C.R.S. § 10-22-101.

We may use the information you provide in computer matching programs with any of the following entities to make eligibility determinations, to verify continued eligibility for enrollment in a qualified health plan, or to process appeals of eligibility determinations:

  * Other verification sources including consumer reporting agencies;
  * Applicants/enrollees, and authorized representatives of applicants/enrollees;
  * Issuers of qualified health plans, as applicable, which are certified by Colorado Division of Insurance;
  * Agents and brokers, as designated or nominated by the applicant/enrollee, who are certified by the Marketplace to assist applicants/enrollees;
  * Financial institutions (banks, credit unions, etc.) including Network Merchants, Inc. for all ACH/ credit card payments;
  * Connect for Health Colorado contractors engaged to perform a function for the Marketplace;
  * Anyone else as required by law.

The Marketplace will also use the information you provide as part of the ongoing operation of this organization, including activities such as performing oversight and quality control activities, combatting fraud, and responding to any concerns about the security or confidentiality of the information. If you are already enrolled through Connect for Health Colorado, we may share your information with other organizations or government agencies when necessary to fulfill a required Exchange minimum function, but we do not sell it.

As part of overall performance and effectiveness monitoring, the Marketplace utilizes Google Analytics to identify and track customer activities to analyze communication campaigns, website navigation, and potential bottlenecks.

For additional information about Google™ Analytics, please see how [Google Uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

We also automatically collect and temporarily store the following types of information about your visits using a variety of Web measurement software tools. The tools collect information automatically and continuously. This information is analyzed and available to designated staff to inform their work in support of the website. This information includes:

  * Domain from which you access the Internet
  * IP address (an IP or internet protocol address is a number that is automatically given to a computer connected to the Web)
  * Operating system on your computer and information about the browser you used when visiting the site
  * Date and time of your visit
  * Pages you visited
  * Address of the website that connected you to connectforhealthco.com (such as google.com or bing.com)

We use this information to measure the number of visitors to our site and its various sections and to help make our site more useful to visitors.

By submitting personal information to Connect for Health Colorado or by using our Sites, you agree that we may collect, use and disclose any such personal information in accordance with this Privacy Statement and as permitted or required by law. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not provide your personal information.

## How Connectforhealthco.com uses cookies

When you visit any website, its server may generate a piece of text known as a “cookie” to place on your computer. The cookie allows the server to “remember” specific information about your visit while you are connected. The cookie makes it easier for you to use the dynamic features of Web pages. Cookies from Connectforhealthco.com pages collect only information about your browser’s visit to the site. They do not collect personal information about you.

There are two types of cookies, single session (temporary), and multi-session (persistent). Session cookies last only as long as your Web browser is open. Once you close your browser, the cookie disappears. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer for longer periods.

How to opt out or disable cookies

If you do not wish to have session or persistent cookies placed on your computer, you can disable them using your Web browser. If you opt out of cookies, you will still have access to all information and resources at Connectforhealthco.com Instructions for disabling or opting out of cookies in the most popular browsers are located at <http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml>.

Please note that by opting out of cookies, you will disable cookies from all sources, not just from Connectforhealthco.com.

## Protection of your data

Connect for Health Colorado has significant protections in place to ensure the privacy of your personal information. The Marketplace system is implemented in compliance with federal and state rules, regulations, and laws designed to protect customer information.

You will be asked to provide only the minimum information necessary to determine eligibility for relevant health plan options. Multiple layers of physical, administrative, and electronic protections have been put in place to protect all information from unauthorized use, access, or malicious activity. Personnel procedures and processes have been developed with an emphasis on privacy.

Connect for Health Colorado (and contractors) adhere to standards as defined in 45 CFR §155.260. Additionally, our customer-support partners — Health Coverage Guides, Assistance Site staff, certified health insurance agents and brokers, and others — must all comply with and support our security and privacy efforts, including security and privacy training, as part of their agreements. Their access to customer data is restricted based on the roles they serve. For example, Health Coverage Guides will not have access to customer data through the Marketplace. Licensed health insurance agents and brokers will have access to portions of client data, but only after completing a certification process and being authorized by the client. Within our own Customer Service Center, representatives will also receive training, screening, and be subject to controls.

Under ACA regulations, any person who knowingly and willfully uses or discloses information in violation of section 1411(g) of the Affordable Care Act will be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 per person or entity, per use or disclosure, in addition to other penalties that may be prescribed by law.

The Marketplace system is tested, inspected, and audited by independent third parties and federal and state organizations. Effective customer privacy and security are a top priority as part of our overall mission to provide this service to Colorado.

You have the right to see whatever information we have about you. You also have the right to have this information corrected if we have any incorrect information on file. To make a request for review of this information, please contact the Privacy and Security Officer using the information provided below.

If you choose to receive alerts or e-newsletters, we collect your email address to complete the subscription process or as your personal identifier.

If you choose to provide us with PII through an email message, request for information, paper or electronic form, questionnaire, survey, etc., we will maintain the information you provide only as long as needed or as required by law.

If in order to contact you we store your personal information in a record system designed to retrieve information about you by personal identifier (name, personal email address, home mailing address, personal or mobile phone number, etc.), we will safeguard the information you provide in accordance with the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. Section 552a). In the event of a disclosure or breach of unsecured personal information we will notify affected individuals. You may request a paper copy of this notice of disclosure.

## How Connectforhealthco.com uses third-party websites and applications

Connectforhealthco.com uses a variety of technologies and social media services to communicate and interact with citizens. These third-party website and application (TPWA) tools include popular social networking and media sites, collaborative software communities, and more. Examples include Facebook®, Twitter™, and YouTube™.

TPWAs are not exclusively operated or controlled by Connectforhealthco.com. Users of TPWAs often share information with the general public, user community, and/or the third party operating the website. These actors may use this information in a variety of ways. TPWAs could cause PII to become available or accessible to Connectforhealthco.com and the public, regardless of whether the information is explicitly asked for or collected by us.

Connectforhealthco.com sometimes collects and uses your PII if you made it available through third-party websites. However, we do not share PII made available through third-party websites. Your activity on the third-party websites we use is governed by the security and privacy policies of those sites. You should review the third-party privacy policies before using the sites and ensure that you understand how your information may be used.

If you have an account with a third-party website and choose to “like,” “friend,” follow, or comment, certain PII associated with your account may be made available to Connectforhealthco.com based on the privacy policy of the third-party website and your privacy settings within that website. You should adjust privacy settings on your account to match your preferences.

Links to other sites

Connectforhealthco.com links to other Colorado sites, other government sites, and to organizations that are involved with required Exchange minimum functions. Once you leave Connectforhealthco.com, you are subject to the privacy policy of the sites you are visiting. Connect for Health Colorado is not responsible for the contents  and privacy under-taking of any non-ConnectforHealthCO.com web page. A hyperlink to a non-ConnectforHealthCO.com web page does not constitute an endorsement.

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**

If we change our privacy policy, the changes will be posted directly to this privacy statement, and any other places we deem appropriate. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time.

If you have questions or suggestions, please contact us at:  
Connect for Health Colorado  
3773 Cherry Creek N. Dr. Suite 1025  
Denver, CO 80209  
1 (720) 496-2530

Privacy@ConnectforHealthCO.com

Effective Date: September 3, 2015
